bookadda.com 2009-05-24

# BookAdda - Online Book Store, Buy Books Online in India,Bookstore India, Online Book Shop: Free Shipping India

---  
  
|   
---  
  |    
As a registered member of BookAdda.com, you will be entitled to savings and benefits on purchase of books. In addition, look forward to receiving monthly newsletters and exclusive promotions offering special deals.  
That's why we've provided this Privacy Policy, which sets forth our policies regarding the collection, use and protection of the personal information of those using the BookAdda.com website. Personal information means information that can be linked to a specific individual, such as name, address, telephone number, e - mail address, and credit card number.   
We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy, and become familiar with it, but you should know that we do not sell or rent our customers' personal information to third parties.  
Please note that we review our Privacy Policy from time to time, and we may make periodic changes to the policy in connection with that review. Therefore, you may wish to bookmark this page and/or periodically review this page to make sure you have the latest version. Regardless of later updates, we will abide by the privacy practices described to you in this Privacy Policy at the time you provided us with your personal information.   
   
This Privacy Policy explains the following:  
   
| [ **What personal information we collect from you and how we use it?**](http://www.bookadda.com/privacy#1)  
| [**What safeguards we have in place to protect your personal information?**](http://www.bookadda.com/privacy#2)  
  |    
|   
---  
| **What personal information we collect from you and how we use it?**  
---  
When browsing our site, you are not required to provide any personal information unless and until you choose to make a purchase or sign up for one of our e-mail newsletters. Making a Purchase In order to purchase a book through our site, you must provide us with certain personal information such as your name, credit card number and expiration date, credit card billing address, telephone number and e - mail address. We require this information to process and fulfill your transactions and keep you informed of each transaction's status.  
If you choose to become a registered member of BookAdda.com site, you must provide your name, address, e-mail address, a unique login name, password, and password validation, and a password hint to help you remember your password. This information is collected on the registration form for several reasons including but not limited to:   
* To allow us to contact you for customer service purposes, if necessary  
* To customize the content of our site to strive to meet your specific needs; and/or   
* To make product or other improvements to our site. In addition, we need your e - mail address to confirm your new member registration. As a BookAdda.com site member you will also occasionally receive updates from us about book sales and promotions, special offers, new BookAdda.com services, and other noteworthy items. However, you may choose at any time to no longer receive these types of e - mail messages. Please see our Opt - Out Policy described below for details.   
   
**Logging of Session Data**  
We automatically log generic information about your computer's connection to the Internet, which we call "session data", that is anonymous and not linked to any personal information. Session data consists of things such as IP address, operating system and type of browser software being used and the activities conducted by the user while on BookAdda.com site. We collect session data because it helps us analyze such things as what items visitors are likely to click on most, the way visitors are clicking through the site, how many visitors are surfing to various pages on the site, how long visitors to the site are staying and how often they are visiting. It also helps us diagnose problems with our servers and lets us better administer our systems.   
   
**Cookies**  
"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. There are many myths circulating about cookies, but you should know that cookies are only read by the server that placed them, and are unable to do such things as run programs on your computer, plant viruses or harvest your personal information. First and foremost, you can rest assured that no personally identifiable information ("PII") about you (e.g., name, address, etc.) is gathered or stored in the cookies placed by the BookAdda.com site and, as a result, none can be passed on to any third parties. Cookies allow us to serve you better and more efficiently, and to personalize your experience at our site.   

**What safeguards we have in place to protect your personal information? ******  
All payments on the BookAdda.com site is SSL secured. This means all personal information you provide to BookAdda.com is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. The same process happens when you make travel purchases on the BookAdda.com site.  
   
**What other information should I know about my privacy?**  
BookAdda.com site contains links to other web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another web site for which BookAdda.com has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of all such sites as their policies may be materially different from this Privacy Policy. Of course, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords, and your BookAdda.com site membership account information.   
In addition to the circumstances described above, BookAdda.com may disclose the site member information if required to do so by law, court order, as requested by other government or law enforcement authority, or in the good faith belief that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable including, without limitation, to protect the rights or properties of BookAdda.com or when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or properties, whether intentionally or otherwise, or when anyone else could be harmed by such activities.  
Of course, you may always submit concerns regarding our Privacy Statement or our privacy practices via email to [customercare@bookadda.com](mailto:customercare@bookadda.com). Please reference the privacy policy in your subject line. BookAdda.com will attempt to respond to all reasonable concerns or inquiries within five business days of receipt.   
Thank you for using BookAdda.com!
